Guide to the Caxton Club Papers, 1923-1930
Department of Special Collections
Caxton Club Papers,
1923-1930
Special Collections M0417
Caxton Club
.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Norman Strouse, 1983.
Historical Note
The Caxton Club was founded in Chicago in 1895 for the literary study and promotion of the arts pertaining to the production of books. Toward this end the Club arranges lectures and exhibits and occasionally publishes books. From the original membership of fifteen, the Club has grown to several hundred members.
Scope and Content Note
Publishing files for two books: 1) Sir Frederic Kenyon's Ancient Books and Modern Discoveries, 1927, and 2) Cyril Davenport's Roger Payne, 1929. Both include correspondence from Bruce Rogers, book designer.
Container List
- Series I. Original material relating to Sir Frederic Kenyon's Ancient Books and Modern Discourses, designed by Bruce Rodgers for the Caxton Club, Chicago, 1927.
  - Six ALS's from Bruce Rodgers to C.L. Ricketts, editor, 1925-1927. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Original typescript with corrections in the author's (Kenyon's) hand, eighty-eight pages. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence relating to the publication of the book, 1923-1929,mostly to and from three members of the Caxton Club's Publication Committee (John T. Lee, C.L. Ricketts, Henry M. Wolf). (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proofs of eight introductory pages, with penciled notes and corrections. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Two prospectuses for the book. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Thirty collotype plate proofs, by Emery Walker. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II. Original material relating to Cyril Davenport's Roger Payne, printed for the Caxton Club, Chicago, 1929.
  - The author's original manuscript, with corrections. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Typical copy of same, thirty-three pages. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Second draft. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Second draft (continued). (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Five sample sheets showing development of title page and text design, including an ALS from Bruce Rodgers, June 8, 1927,re the book design and the design of the club device. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Two sets of page proofs; one with Ricketts' penciled corrections, the second with the corrections printed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Material related to prints and plates. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Eleven silverprints. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Seven prints. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Thirty-five prints. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thirty-five prints. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence relating to the publication of the book, 1926-1930,primarily to C.L. Ricketts, from Cyril Davenport, John T. Lee, Henry M. Wolf, and others.
  - Prospectus and related correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ricketts' Davenport correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence on book, Ricketts' files May 21, 1928 to November 23, 1928. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence on book, Ricketts' files December 4, 1928 to October 7, 1929. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence on book, Ricketts' files October 10, 1929 to April 15, 1930. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Two prints and three negatives. (Box 2, Folder 6)